Guide to the Vassar College Student Materials Collection, 1859-2025 (bulk 1867-1950)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Student Materials Collection
1859-2025
1867-1950
Vassar College
approximately 248.2 cubic feet (213 boxes, 698 volumes, 1 OV folder)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Diaries, letters, scrapbooks, photograph albums and other materials documenting student life at Vassar College.
Administrative History
Vassar College was founded in 1861 and opened its doors in 1865.
Scope and Content Note
Diaries, letters, scrapbooks, photograph albums and other materials documenting student life at Vassar College.
The diaries concern life on campus, other students, classes, relationships with their professors, vacations, family news, and other subjects; some volumes have short entries on daily activities while others have longer, more reflective entries.
The letters were written by students to family, friends, and Vassar faculty, with some letters received by students from family and friends, concerning life at Vassar, their studies, social events, and family affairs.
The scrapbooks contain programs, notices, invitations, and other memorabilia compiled by students.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Manuscript collections in the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library contain additional materials for the following former students: Anderson, Harriet (VC 1903), Barnum, Charlotte C. (VC 1881), Bishop, Elizabeth H. (VC 1897), Burchard, Anna T. (VC 1897), Carroll, Ruth (Robinson) (VC 1922), Churchill, Ruth (Hornblower) (VC 1908), Clark, Frances (Underhill) (VC 1891), Collier, Laura H. (Brownell) (VC 1874), Cooley, Nellie (Wooster) (VC 1886), Cutler, Ruth E. (VC 1907), Delmas, Gladys (Krieble) (VC 1935), Dewees, Edith (Hilles) (VC 1914), Dodge, Josephine (Jewell) (VC Ex 1875), Fitt, Harriet (Bradley) (VC 1913), Gay, Mary W. (VC Ex 1881), Grove, Elsa (Butler) (VC 1905), Hadley, Helen Morris (VC 1883), Houts, Annie (Glidden) (VC 1869), Janish, Jeanne (Russell) (VC 1924), Kenyon, Helen (VC 1905), Lutz, Alma (VC 1912), McCaleb, Ella (VC 1878), McCarthy, Mary (Fitt) (VC 1941), Milholland, Inez (VC 1909), Raymond, Cornelia M. (VC 1882), Richards, Ellen H. (Swallow) (VC 1870), Ryerson, Margery A. (VC 1909), Scott, Mary Augusta (VC 1876), Sherwin, Martha May (Reynolds) (VC 1915), Tag, Florence K. (VC 1911), Thompson, Mary (Thaw) (VC 1877), Valentine, Gertrude C. (VC 1912), Vance, Gertrude (Pratt) (VC Ex 1917), Wesbrook, Elizabeth (Barney) (VC 1912), Wesbrook, Mary E. (VC 1935), Wheeler, Jessie F. (VC 1882), Wislocki, Florence (Clothier) (VC 1926), and Wright, Margaret C. (VC 1908).
Student materials of Gertrude Mary Bullard, Class of 1908, can be found in the Bullard Family Papers, Folklife Center of the Crandall Library, Glens Falls, NY.
Student materials of Margaret H. (Laidlaw) Richardson, Class of 1923, can be found in the Margaret H. Laidlaw Richardson Papers.
Separated Materials
Photograph albums no. 260 and 278 (Margaret De M. Brown) removed and added to the Margaret De M. Brown Photographs, April 2008.
Photograph album no. 261 (Frances Wood) removed and added to the Frances A. Wood Papers, April 2008.
Photograph album no. 267 (Warren Kay Vantine) removed and added to the Warren Kay Vantine Photographs, April 2008.
Photograph albums no. 266 and former no. 268 (Vail Brothers) removed and added to the Vail Brothers Photograph Albums, circa 2010.
Photograph album of Laura H. (Brownell) Collier removed and added to the Laura Brownell Collier Papers, circa 2016.
Photograph album no. 153 (VC 1894 — Nollen, Emeline (Bartlett)) removed and added to manuscript collection Emeline Bartlett Nollen Scrapbook (VC 1894), December 2018.
Photograph album no. 162 (VC 1903 — Anderson, Harriet) removed and added to the Harriet Anderson Papers (VC 1903), December 2018.
Photograph album no. 259 (Miscellany News) removed and added to the Philalethan Society Records, 2019.
Two diaries with photocopies and one letter from Christine Ladd-Franklin [Box 135] were removed and added to the Christine Ladd-Franklin Papers, January 2023.
Five scrapbooks, "55th Reunion Scrapbook (VC 1919), 1974," "Class of 1910 Scrapbook," "Senior Parlor Guestbook (VC 1922)," "Senior Parlor Guestbook (VC 1923)," and "Class of 1936 Commencement Scrapbook, presented to Louise Mason (VC Spec 1889-1991) in honor of Sarah Floyd (VC 1936)" were removed and added to the Vassar College Class Records.
Subject Headings
Names:
Adams, Ruth; Anthony, Constance E.; Bishop, Harriette Warner, 1845-1944; Bromley, Frances M.; Brydon, Anne Page; Chase, G. Louise (Fletcher); Delmas, Gladys Krieble, 1913-1991; Eldridge, Muriel Tilden; Furness, Caroline E. (Caroline Ellen), 1869-1936; Holden, Abby (Rankin); Johns, Roberta T.; Keffer, Bertha; Kenyon, Helen; MacCoy, Marjorie Newell; Markwick, Marjorie (Anthony); Martin, Elma G.; May, Sybil Huntington; McGirr, Alice Thurston; McGraw, Maria Dickinson, 1843-1920; Milholland, Inez; Murphy, Lois Barclay, 1902-2003; Pease, Helen Hartley; Raymond, Cornelia M., 1861-1952; Scott, Mary Augusta, 1851-1918; Shipp, Margaret M.; Skinner, Laura A.; Smith, Sidney (Lewis); Thompson, Mary Thaw, 1856-1944; Townsend, Fanny (Simpson); Valentine, Gertrude C.; Vance, Gertrude R. Ladd (Pratt); Warner, Helen F.; Wislocki, Florence (Clothier); Wyman, Anne (Southworth)
Organizations:
Vassar College--Students; Vassar College--Faculty
Subjects:
Women--Diaries; Women college students--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women college teachers--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie
Places:
Poughkeepsie (N.Y.)--History
Document Types:
Account books; Autograph albums; Correspondence; Diaries; Drawings (visual works); Essays; Examinations (documents); Notebooks; Photograph albums; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Syllabi
VCL Categories:
Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke and Laura Streett, April 2008. Updated by Mark Seidl, November 2019-January 2020. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, November 2022 - May 2025.
Acquisition Information
Multiple donors in multiple accessions.
Other Formats
Transcripts available for some correspondence.
Many early diaries, letters, scrapbooks, and photograph albums are available via the Vassar College Libraries' Digital Library.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 12 series, each arranged by class year. Materials with an unknown creator or class year are filed at the end of each series.
Series List
- Series I. Account Books and Bills, circa 1882-1955; [0.4 cubic feet (2 boxes)]
- Series II. Autograph Albums, circa 1865-1899; [1 cubic foot (5 boxes)]
- Series III. Diaries, 1860-1936; [2.6 cubic feet (13 boxes)]
- Series IV. Examinations, 1879-1943; [0.6 cubic feet (3 boxes)]
- Series V. Letters, 1859 - circa 1960; [22.4 cubic feet (114 boxes)]
- Series VI. Notebooks, 1866-1974; [14.45 cubic feet (52 boxes)]
- Series VII. Notecards, circa 1897-circa 1950; [1.5 cubic feet (8 boxes)]
- Series VIII. Papers, 1860-1984; [3.2 cubic feet (14 boxes, 1 volume)]
- Series IX. Scrapbooks, 1871-1963; [approximately 148.6 cubic feet (362 volumes)]
- Series X. Syllabi, 1914-1940; [0.2 cubic feet (1 box)]
- Series XI. Photograph Albums, 1865-circa 1989; [approximately 52.4 cubic feet (336 volumes)]
- Series XII. Artwork and Projects, 2025; [1 OV folder]
Container List
- SERIES I. ACCOUNT BOOKS and BILLS, circa 1882-1955
  - VC 1882 — Wyman, Anne (Southworth) (Box 180)
  - VC 1894 — Boyce, Josephine (Delaney) (Box 180)
  - VC Ex 1896 — DeWitt, Nettie (Brand) (Box 180)
  - VC 1899 — Waterman, Helen (Blumenthal) (Box 180)
  - VC 1906 — Kosmopoulos, [Alice] Leslie (Walker) (Box 180)
  - VC 1908 — Robinson, Gertrude (Bullard) (Box 180)
  - VC 1912 — Baker, Anne (Box 180)
  - VC 1915 — Gannett, Mary (Ross) (Box 180)
  - VC 1915 — Sherwin, Martha May (Reynolds) (Box 181)
  - VC 1916 — Rannells, Marion E. (Box 181)
  - VC 1918 — Pease, Helen Hartley (Box 181)
  - VC 1941 — Richards, Martha (Dilks) (Box 181)
  - VC 1958 — Payne, Belinda J. Pope — Invoices, 1954-1955 (Box 212)
- SERIES II. AUTOGRAPH ALBUMS, circa 1865-1899
  - VC 1865-1866 — Alexander, Margaret S., circa 1866 (Box 87)
  - VC 1865-1866 — Metcalf, Elizabeth Henshaw, circa 1866 (Box 87)
  - VC 1865-1866 — Towne, Isabel (Treadwell), circa 1866 (Box 87)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Cathcart, Alice (Morrison), circa 1866 (Box 86)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Galpin, Caroline M., circa 1866 (Box 89)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Sexton, Harriet J., circa 1866 (Box 87)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Shattuck, Mandana M. [Prof. of Botany, 1866-1870], undated (Box 86)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Slade, Abigail L. and Caroline E., circa 1866 (Box 87)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Smyser, Ellen Louise, circa 1866 (Box 86)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Taylor, Anna, circa 1866 (Box 85)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Worman, Emma (Davis), circa 1866 (Box 88)
  - VC Jan 1866-1866 — Van Horne, Marsella, circa 1866 (Box 86)
  - VC 1865-1867 [Special] — Hart, Florence A., circa 1867 (Box 89)
  - VC 1865-1867 [Special] — Kinsey, May S., circa 1867 (Box 88)
  - VC 1866-1867 [Special] — Camp, Annetta Hortense, circa 1867 (Box 85)
  - VC 1866-1867 [Special] — Hulse, Susie, circa 1867 (Box 86)
  - VC 1866 - Jan 1867 [Preparatory] — Warner, Mary Elizabeth, circa 1867 (Box 87)
  - VC 1867 [Special] — Barrett, Sarah Emily, circa 1867 (Box 89)
  - VC 1868 — Warner, Helen F., circa 1868 (Box 88)
  - VC 1865-1868 [Special] — Cornell, Mary Emma, circa 1868 (Box 84)
  - VC 1867-1868 [Preparatory] — Moyer, Florence, circa 1868 (Box 85)
  - VC 1867-1869 [Preparatory] — Davis, Mary Ella Parsons, circa 1869 (Box 85)
  - VC 1867-1869 [Special] — Trask, Mary, circa 1869 (Box 85)
  - VC 1870 — Coffin, Elizabeth R., circa 1870 (Box 88)
  - VC 1870 — Morgan, Lillie Merrick, 1866-1870 (Box 212)
  - VC Ex 1870 — Powers, Catherine (Jones) [Prep 1865-1868, Spec 1868-1869], circa 1870 (Box 84)
  - VC 1869-1870 [Special] — Marvin, Julia K., circa 1870 (Box 88)
  - VC 1871 — Hopper, Euphemia W., circa 1871 (Box 86)
  - VC 1871 — House, Mary C., circa 1871 (Box 88)
  - VC 1871-1872 [Preparatory] — Hays, Mary Virginia, circa 1872 (Box 87)
  - VC 1873 — Richardson, Mary (Raymond), circa 1873 (Box 84)
  - VC Ex 1875 — Burd, Abbie Maria (Crosman), circa 1873 (Box 89)
  - VC Ex 1875 — Kiersted, Mary (Pidgeon), circa 1873 (Box 85)
  - VC Ex 1875 — Munroe, Hannah E., 1870-1871 (Box 84)
  - VC 1876 — Adams, Mary Louise "Minnie" (Kellogg), circa 1876 (Box 85)
  - VC Ex 1877 — Rickards, Virginia, circa 1877 (Box 85)
  - VC 1878 — MacAlpin, Jessie (Davis), circa 1878 (Box 89)
  - VC 1878 - Oct 1880 [Preparatory] — Howard, Louisa (Thayer), circa 1880 (Box 85)
  - VC Ex 1881 — Alvord, Evelyn (Fletcher) [1876-1878 (Preparatory); 1878-1880 (Painting)], circa 1881 (Box 84)
  - [VC 1881 — Durand, Helene S.?], autograph and question book, 1871-1875 (Box 84)
  - VC 1883-1886 [Art] — Beyer, Caroline (Rabe), circa 1886 (Box 84)
  - VC 1899 — Little, Marou S. (Brown), circa 1899 (Box 84)
  - VC Unknown — Campbell, Jennie M. G., undated (Box 85)
- SERIES III. DIARIES, 1860-1936
  Most of the early diaries are available online via the Vassar College Libraries' Digital Library.
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Slade, Abigail L. (Box 120)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Slade, Caroline E. (Box 120)
  - VC 1869 — Ladd-Franklin, Christine [see the Christine Ladd-Franklin Papers ], 1860-1873
  - VC 1869 — Stilson, Sarah L., 1865-1869, 1909 (Box 120)
  - VC 1870 — Adee, Ellen (Skeel), 1869-1870 (Box 120)
  - VC 1871 — Raymond, Susan, 1864-1871 (Box 120)
  - VC 1873 — Elder, Lilla (Thomas), 1886 May - 1872 May (Box 127)
  - VC Ex 1874 — James, Fannie (Shouse) [transcript only], circa 1960s-1970s (Box 133)
  - VC Ex 1875 — Pidgeon, Mary (Kiersted), 1871 (Box 120)
  - VC 1876 — Holden, Abby (Rankin), 1871 July - 1872 June (Box 121)
  - VC 1876 — Keffer, Bertha, with notes, 1871 January - June (Box 121)
  - VC 1876 — Keffer, Bertha (Box 121)
  - VC 1876 — Robinson, Mary Barber, 1873 (Box 203)
  - VC Ex 1879 — Bromley, Frances M., 1870-1877 (Box 130)
  - VC Ex 1879 — Bromley, Frances M., 1872 (Box 122)
  - VC Ex 1879 — Bromley, Frances M., 1873 (Box 122)
  - VC Ex 1879 — Bromley, Frances M., 1874 (Box 122)
  - VC Ex 1879 — Bromley, Frances M., 1875 (Box 122)
  - VC Ex 1879 — Bromley, Frances M., 1876 (Box 122)
  - VC Ex 1879 — Bromley, Frances M., 1876-1877 (Box 122)
  - VC Ex 1879 — Bromley, Frances M., 1877 (Box 122)
  - VC Ex 1879 — Bromley, Frances M. — to "Edith", 1880-1882 (Box 130)
  - VC Ex 1881 — Gay, Mary W., 1878 (Box 124)
  - VC 1882 — Elwell, Abbie (Nickerson), 1878-1880 (Box 123)
  - VC 1882 — Wyman, Anne (Southworth), 1878-1880 (Box 123)
  - VC 1882 — Wyman, Anne (Southworth), 1880-1882 (Box 123)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1893 (Box 125)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1894 (Box 125)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1895 (Box 125)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1896 (Box 125)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1897 (Box 125)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1898 (Box 125)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1899 (Box 126)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1900 (Box 126)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1901 (Box 126)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1902 (Box 126)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1903 (Box 127)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1904 (Box 127)
  - VC 1883 — Raymond, Cornelia M., 1905 (Box 127)
  - VC 1887 — Guttman, Ida (Frank), 1883 September - December (Box 124)
  - VC 1891 — Van Tassel, Nellie E., 1887 Feb - 1888 Jun; [photocopies only] (Box 132)
  - VC 1892-1893 [Special] — Martin, Elma G., 1892-1907 (Box 124)
  - VC 1895 — Earl, Mary (Reed) [photocopies only], 1891-1895 (Box 132)
  - VC 1898 — Haight, Helen I., undated (Box 124)
  - VC 1913 — Ordway, Katherine Gretta, 1909-1910 (Box 129)
  - VC 1913 — Ordway, Katherine Gretta, 1910-1911 (Box 129)
  - VC 1913 — Ordway, Katherine Gretta, 1911-1912 (Box 129)
  - VC 1913 — Ordway, Katherine Gretta, 1912-1913 (Box 130)
  - VC 1913 — Ordway, Katherine Gretta, 1913-1914 (Box 130)
  - VC 1916 — Markwick, Marjorie (Anthony), 1914 (Box 131)
  - VC 1917 — Anthony, Constance E., 1915 (Box 131)
  - VC 1917 — Pollock, Mary (Culver), 1913-1917 (Box 131)
  - VC 1918 — Pease, Helen Hartley, 1914-1915 (Box 128)
  - VC 1920 — Judd, Dorothy (Leonard), 1917 (Box 130)
  - VC 1925 — Brydon, Anne Page, 1922 (Box 128)
  - VC 1925 — Brydon, Anne Page, 1923 (Box 128)
  - VC 1925 — Jacoby, Ruth Burtner, 1922-1925 (Box 212)
  - VC 1926 — Wislocki, Florence (Clothier), 1922 October 17-30 (Box 130)
  - VC 1936 — Kernan, Sophia, 1936 July - September (Box 130)
- SERIES IV. EXAMINATIONS, 1879-1943
  - VC 1913 — Ordway, Katherine Gretta — Exam questions and notebook, unknown Prof., 1909-1913 (Box 79)
  - VC 1914 — Crane, Mary P. — Ethics, Prof. Zita Thornbury, undated (Box 79)
  - VC 1914 — Grant, Frances Louise — Ethics, Prof. Zita Thornbury, undated (Box 79)
  - VC 1914 — Haviland, Constance — Ethics, Prof. Zita Thornbury, undated (Box 79)
  - VC 1914 — Hollister, Martha C. — Ethics, Prof. Zita Thornbury, undated (Box 79)
  - VC 1914 — Howland, Martha — Ethics exam and addendum, Prof. Zita Thornbury, undated (Box 79)
  - VC 1914 — Lyall, Gladys — Ethics, Prof. Zita Thornbury, undated (Box 79)
  - VC 1914 — McLaughlin, Margaret — Ethics, Prof. Zita Thornbury, undated (Box 79)
  - VC 1914 — Pratt, Katharine — Ethics, Prof. Zita Thornbury, undated (Box 79)
  - VC 1914 — Rice, Mary Hayes — Ethics, Prof. Zita Thornbury, undated (Box 79)
  - VC 1914 — Spencer, Gladys M. — Ethics, Prof. Zita Thornbury, undated (Box 79)
  - VC 1914 — Wilson, Katherine — Ethics exam and addendum, Prof. Zita Thornbury, undated (Box 79)
  - VC 1915 — Mattice, Marion B. — Ethics exam and addendum, Prof. Zita Thornbury, undated (Box 79)
  - VC 1923 — Richardson, Margaret H. (Laidlaw) — French, Latin, Mathematics, Philosophy, Physics, and Zoology, unknown professors [see Margaret H. Laidlaw Richarson Papers ], 1920-1922
  - VC 1924 — Goldmark, Maxine — English, German, Physical Education, Psychology, unknown professors, 1920; (includes ephemera) (Box 203)
  - VC 1924 — Kuhs, Evelyn M. — German, Latin, Math, English, unknown professors, 1920 (Box 79)
  - VC 1944 — Van Arsdale, Sallie Welsh — Economics, unknown professor, 1942 (Box 79)
  - Miscellaneous exam questions, 1879-1903 (Box 134)
  - Miscellaneous exam questions, 1894-1898, undated (Box 179)
  - Miscellaneous examinations, 1901-1943, undated (Box 79)
  - Miscellaneous examinations, 1901-1943, undated (Box 79)
- SERIES V. LETTERS, 1859 - circa 1960
  Many of the early letters are available via the Vassar College Libraries' Digital Library.
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Arnzen, Laura Earl — to Caroline E. and Abigail L. Slade, 1865 Fall; (3 letters) (Box 64)
  - VC 1865-1868 [Special] — Cornell, Mary Emma — to father, 1866 June 14; (1 letter) (Box 65)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Fales, Helen Augusta — to "dear Aunt Susan" [transcript], 1865 November 18; (1 letter) (Box 141)
  - VC 1865-1867 [Special] — Foster, Frances (Harmon) Miller — to Jennie Elizabeth Clark and Louisa Burton, 1865-1866; (6 items) (Box 68)
  - VC 1865-1867 [Special]— Gallup, Lillie (Taylor) — to parents, 1867 June 9; (2 letters) (Box 68)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Holtz, Eliza — to family, (3 letters) (Box 70)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — McClintock, Margaretta — from family and friends inc. Frances Goodenow, Mary McCune, Margaretta Poague, Cornelia Tooker, and Carrie Vassar, 1859-1891 (Boxes 192-193)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Sawyer, Kitty — to Miss Belle Greene Sawyer, 1866 March; (1 letter) (Box 72)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Slade, Abigail L. — to "Mamie", 1866 April 25; (1 letter) (Box 72)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Slade, Abigail L. — to Mary Slade (sister), 1866 June 18; (1 letter) (Box 72)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Slade, Abigail L. — to mother, 1866 May 6; (1 letter) (Box 72)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Slade, Caroline E. — to family, 1866 February - May; (9 letters) (Box 72)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Slade, Abigail L. and/or Slade, Caroline E. — to family, 1866 January - June; (6 letters) (Box 72)
  - VC 1865-1869 [Special] — [Stewart, Helen "Nellie" W.?] — to sister "Mary", 1867 November 3; (1 letter) (Box 64)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Sylvester, Helen (Seymour) — to family, (24 letters) (Box 73)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Sylvester, Helen (Seymour) — to family, [transcripts] (Box 73)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Preparatory] — Thompson, Mary (Coe) — to Mrs. Boynton, 1865 November; (1 letter) (Box 74)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Towne, Isabel (Treadwell) — from friends, 1865-1869; [transcripts] (Box 212)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Towne, Isabel (Treadwell) — from "Nellie G.", 1866 September 17; (1 letter) (Box 212)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Towne, Isabel (Treadwell) — from "Julie", 1869 October 17; (1 letter) (Box 212)
  - VC 1865-1866 [Special] — Williams, Ellen (Boardman) — to family, 1865 September - 1866 June; (49 letters) (Box 22)
  - VC 1866-1867 [Special] — Anderson, Irene — to Norton B. Anderson, 1866 October 10; (1 letter) (Box 64)
  - VC 1866-1867 [Special] — Camp, Annetta Hortense — to Abigail L. Slade (1865-1866 Special), 1867 January; (1 letter) (Box 65)
  - VC 1866-1867 [Special] — Badgley, Mary M. — to Kate Flanders, 1866 September - 1867 January; (7 letters) (Box 64)
  - VC 1866-1867 [Special] — Brown, Francis Elizabeth — to Caroline E. and Abigail L. Slade (VC 1865-1866), (7 letters) (Box 64)
  - VC 1866-1867 [Preparatory]; 1867 — Neef, Nora — to Abbie Farwell (VC 1872), 1866 November; (1 letter) (Box 71)
  - VC 1866-1867 [Special] — Wood, Fanny E. — to Aunt Villa, 1866 March 29; (1 letter) (Box 64)
  - VC 1867 — Bishop, Harriette A. (Warner) — to family, 1866 January - October; (11 letters) (Box 63)
  - VC 1867 — McGraw, Maria (Dickinson) — to Harriette (Warner) Bishop, Helen Warner, and Martha Warner, 1866 December 23; (1 letter) (Box 71)
  - VC 1867 — McGraw, Maria (Dickinson) — to Thomas S. McGraw, 1867 May 15; (1 letter) (Box 71)
  - VC 1867-1868 [Special] — Teegarden, Mary Treat — to family, 1867 December; (1 letter) (Box 74)
  - VC 1868 — Bates, Sarah Glazier — to Isabel (Treadwell) Towne (1865-1866 Special), 1867-1870; (9 letters) (Box 64)
  - VC 1868 — Blatchley, Sarah Louise — to Isabel (Treadwell) Towne (1865-1866 Special), 1865-1867; (4 letters) (Box 64)
  - VC 1868 — Griggs, Mary Beulah — between parents concerning Mary Griggs' illness, 1870 (Box 207)
  - VC 1868 — Warner, Helen F. — to family, 1867; (5 letters) (Box 63)
  - VC 1868 — Warner, Martha S. — to family, (83 letters) (Box 63)
  - VC 1868-1869 [Preparatory]; 1869-1870 [Special] — Chase, Almira (Cowles) — to mother, (1 letter) (Box 65)
  - VC 1868-1869 [Preparatory]; 1869-1870 [Special] — Taylor, Kate (Huntington) — to "Sue", 1869 February 8; (1 letter) (Box 64)
  - VC 1869 — [Bagg, Sophia D. or Sophia R. Burnham] — to Annie M. Glidden (VC 1869), undated; (1 letter) (Box 64)
  - VC 1869 — Houts, Annie (Glidden) — to family, 1865-1869; (30 letters) (Box 70)
  - VC 1869-1870 [Preparatory] — Adams, Juliet Amelia — to Minnie McInnes, 1869 September 16; (1 letter) (Box 64)
  - VC 1870 — Cole, Elizabeth (Curtis) — to Mattie, 1870 June 15; (1 letter) (Box 65)
  - VC 1870 — Mineah, Mary A. — to mother, 1869-1870; (2 letters) (Box 71)
  - VC 1870 — Richards, Ellen H. (Swallow) — to mother, 1869 April 9; (1 letter) (Box 64)
  - VC 1870 — Slocum, Harriet (Palmer) — to Mollie, 1869 April 21; (1 letter) (Box 72)
  - VC 1870 — Woodworth, Mary (Parker) — to family [photocopies], 1867-1869; (38 letters) (Box 23)
  - VC 1870-1871 [Special] — Washburn, Lucy M. — to Alvah, 1871 February 23; (1 letter) (Box 75)
  - VC 1870-1871 [Special] — Fogg, Annie — to "friend Annie", 1870 September 18; (1 letter) (Box 68)
  - VC 1872 — DeCaindry, Ida (Corson) — to Helen (sister), 1870-1871; (3 letters) (Box 66)
  - VC 1872 — DeCaindry, Ida (Corson) — to family, friends, 1861-1875, undated (Boxes 169-170)
  - VC 1872 — Stem, Sarah M. — to family, 1868-1871; (9 letters) (Box 73)
  - VC 1873 — Moore, Felicia E. — to sister, 1870 November 27; (1 letter) (Box 71)
  - VC 1874 — Barus, Annie Howes — to Edith, 1869 September 15; (1 letter) (Box 64)
  - VC 1874 — Hoyt, Emma L. — to Mrs. Reed, 1872 April 7; (2 letters) (Box 70)
  - VC 1875 — Barnes, Lucy (Sellers) — to family, George Taylor Barnes, 1870-1875; (17 letters) (Box 64)
  - VC 1875 — Hollister, Emma B. — to mother, 1871; (2 letters) (Box 70)
  - VC 1875 — Pease, Julia M. — to family [photocopies], 1870 September - 1872 December (Box 36)
  - VC 1875 — Pease, Julia M. — to family [photocopies], 1873 January - 1875 (Box 37)
  - VC 1875 — Tappan, Eva March — to mother, 1874; (7 letters) (Box 73)
  - VC 1875-1876 [Preparatory] — Thompson, Addie (Adda) — to family, (13 letters) (Box 74)
  - VC Ex 1875 — Dodge, Josephine (Jewell) — to Mae [transcript only, originals in Dodge Collection], 1871-1872 (Box 67)
  - VC 1876 — Robinson, Mary B. — to Pres John H. Raymond, 1872 September 25; (1 letter) (Box 72)
  - VC Ex 1876 — Ladd, Jennie A. — to family and Julie [photocopies], 1872-1873; (4 letters) (Box 71)
  - VC Ex 1878 — Gaston, Mary E. — to her mother, 1874-1875; (17 letters) (Box 68)
  - VC 1877 — Griffis, Katharine (Stanton) — to Mary Grace Toll Hill, 1875, [1879?]; (4 letters) (Box 69)
  - VC 1877 — MacCoy, Emma (Logan) — to and from family, "Lizzie," W. D. Logan, Bessie McKnight, Margie McKnight and Lucy O'Hara, 1872 September - December (Box 71)
  - VC 1877 — Thompson, Mary (Thaw) — to father, 1873-1876; (4 letters) (Box 74)
  - VC 1878-1879 [Special] — Moore, Lulu L. — to father [photocopy], 1878 December 31; (1 letter) (Box 71)